ocls.info 2017-03-25

# Orange County Library System Privacy Policy The Orange County Library System is committed to protecting the privacy of your personal information as well as information regarding your individual use of the Library or its services. The policy outlined below addresses some specific privacy concerns.

                      Orange County Library System Privacy Policy
The Orange County Library System is committed to protecting the privacy of your
personal information as well as information regarding your individual use of the
Library or its services. The policy outlined below addresses some specific privacy
concerns.
Information We Collect
The registration information acquired by the Library for the purpose of allowing a
patron to borrow books and other materials is limited to what we believe is
necessary or useful to conduct Library business. Personal information gathered such
as name, address, phone number, e-mail address, photo and driver’s license number
are gathered for the purpose of identification and accountability for use of Library
materials. The registration information required by the Library is confidential and
exempt from a public records request.
Records of Library use (i.e. quantity of or titles of materials checked out and
returned or services used) are maintained only for the purpose of statistics or for the
business purpose of recovering materials or fees. Users at their own discretion may
choose to activate the “Reading History” option online which will create a history of
items checked out on that account. This is information not otherwise maintained by
the Library. The Library may ask for an e-mail address for the purpose of sending
advance “about to be due” electronic notices, overdue notices, program
announcements or other Library news.
From time to time, we may use personal information, for Library purposes only, for
new unanticipated uses not previously disclosed in our privacy notice. If our
information practices do change, we will post the policy changes on our website to
notify you and provide you with the ability to opt out of these new uses. If you have
any concerns about how your information is used, please contact us at
comments@ocls.info.
Protecting Information About You
Personal information requested by the Library and information regarding a card
holder’s use of the Library is protected by Florida Statute 257.261       According to
this statute this information may be turned over to a third party for the purpose of
collecting materials, fines or fees owed the Library. This information is also subject
to the provisions of Section 215 the USA PATRIOT Act which provides the federal
government with the ability to request such records.
Please be aware of the fact that choosing to activate the “Reading History” option for
your account creates a record which is accessible by both of the above mentioned
exceptions to the general privacy of your record.
The Library will not sell, lease or otherwise share any personal information to outside
parties except as outlined above or unless required by law.
Use of the Library’s Web Site
When you visit the Library's web site, we collect and store only information to
measure the number of visitors to different areas of our sites to assist us in making
our sites more useful to you. This information includes:
Approved by the Library Board of Trustees November 9, 2006

            o  The address (IP) of your computer or internet provider
            o  The date and time you accessed our site
            o  The Internet address of the web site that referred you to our site.
The Library's web sites use "cookies" to allow you access to certain functions ( such
as the on-line catalog and electronic resources, etc) within our sites. These cookie
files do not capture any personal user information (such as e-mail address or user
passwords). Some of our subscription databases such as Learn A Test do use
“cookies”.
Some of the Library web sites/pages contain links to external sites not maintained by
the Library. The Library cannot be responsible for your privacy when you disclose
information to outside web sites. It is your responsibility to protect your personal
information.
Miscellaneous Records
Records, including but not limited to, correspondence with the Library or reports of
incidents at the Library are considered public records as set forth in subsection
119.011(11) of the Florida Statutes.
E-mail Communications with the Library
E-mail addresses gathered as part of your Library registration are confidential and
exempt from a public record request as set forth in subsection 257.261(1) of the
Florida Statutes. E-mail communications with the Library and the e-mail addresses
associated with them are a public record.
Visitors to our website should be aware that the Library complies with the following
required posting to our website.
668.6076 Public records status of e-mail addresses; agency website
notice.--Any agency, as defined in s. 119.011, or legislative entity that operates a
website and uses electronic mail shall post the following statement in a conspicuous
location on its website:
Under Florida law, e-mail addresses are public records. If you do not want your e-
mail address released in response to a public records request, do not send electronic
mail to this entity. Instead, contact this office by phone or in writing.
Additionally the Library places the following message on all outgoing email.
Florida has a very broad Public Records Law. Virtually all written communications to
or from State and Local officials are public records available to the public and media
upon request. The Orange County Library System policy does not differentiate
between personal and business emails. E-mail sent via any Library-owned system
will be considered public and will only be withheld from disclosure if deemed
confidential pursuant to State Law.
Approved by the Library Board of Trustees November 9, 2006
